<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Proposals for the printing a grand abridgment of all the common statute law of England to this present year, 1674 / by W. Sheppard Esquire.</title>
            <author>Sheppard, William, d. 1675?</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1674</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B10023</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S3209BA</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224408</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">69648940</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 69648940</idno>
            <idno type="VID">185089</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B10023)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 185089)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2886:16)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Proposals for the printing a grand abridgment of all the common statute law of England to this present year, 1674 / by W. Sheppard Esquire.</title>
                  <author>Sheppard, William, d. 1675?</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1674]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Harvard University. Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Law --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Law --  Digests --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-07</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-07</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:185089:1"/>
            <head>PROPOSALS FOR THE PRINTING A GRAND ABRIDGMENT Of all the <hi>Common</hi> and <hi>Statute LAW</hi> of <hi>England</hi> to this preſent Year, 1674. By <hi>W. Sheppard</hi> Eſquire.</head>
            <argument>
               <p>Allowed of by Authority.</p>
            </argument>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HE above mentioned <hi>Author</hi> formerly publiſhed an <hi>Eſſay</hi> in this kind, entituled, <hi>An Epitome,</hi> &amp;c. which <hi>Book</hi> had ſo good a reception from the Learned in the Law, that the <hi>Author</hi> had encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to undertake a more Comprehenſive Work of the ſame nature <hi>(being an Abridgment of all the Old and New Law,</hi> as well <hi>Common</hi> as <hi>Statute</hi> to <hi>this preſent year</hi> 1674.) and hath imployed the greateſt part of his time theſe Fourteen years laſt paſt, in compiling this ſo great and neceſſary a Work now finiſhed.</p>
            <p>And that the ſaid Book might be of general uſe, it is <hi>Writ in the Engliſh Tongue,</hi> and ſo methodized in an Alphabetical Order under proper Heads with Quotations out of the <hi>Common</hi> and <hi>Statute Law,</hi> for confirma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of what is writ, that not only the Profeſſors of the Law, but all others, may have a <hi>Sure Guide</hi> upon all occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions readily to find out what is in the <hi>Common</hi> or <hi>Statute Law</hi> of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And whereas the ſaid Book <hi>(now Printing at three Printing-houſes)</hi> will conſiſt of two Volumes Print<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed according to the <hi>Specimen;</hi> the Charges whereof will be very great: Therefore the Undertakers, for an invita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to all thoſe that will Aſſiſt in carrying on ſo Great and Neceſſary a Work, <hi>Propoſe</hi> as followeth:
<list>
                  <item>1. <hi>That whoſoever will ſubſcribe, and pay into the hands of any one of the Perſons here undernamed, the Summe of 27 s. in manner and form following, ſhall be intituled to a complete Book in Quires,</hi> viz. 10 s. <hi>in hand to be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed towards the preſent Charge, and 17 s. more when the ſaid Book ſhall be finiſhed and delivered accordingly.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>II. <hi>And for the Security of all perſons that ſhall ſubſcribe to any of the parties here under-named, the party who ſhall receive ſuch ſubſcription will give a Bill under his hand and ſeal for the delivery of the ſaid Book when Printed, upon payment of the ſaid ſummes in manner aforeſaid.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>III. <hi>Note, That the ſaid Book will not be ſold for leſs than 40 s. Bound to any but the Subſcribers.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Henry Twyford,</hi> in <hi>Vine Court, Middle Temple.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Thomas Baſſett,</hi> at the <hi>George,</hi> near St. <hi>Dunſtan</hi>'s Church in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet,</hi> and in <hi>Weſtminſter-Hall.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>William Lee,</hi> at the <hi>Turks-Head</hi> in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Francis Tyton,</hi> at the <hi>Three Daggers</hi> in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Thomas Parkburſt,</hi> at the <hi>Three Bibles</hi> in <hi>Cheapſide.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Rob. Horne,</hi> at the <hi>South-Entrance</hi> of the <hi>Royal-Exchange.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Henry Brome,</hi> at the <hi>Gun, Weſt-End</hi> of St. <hi>Pauls.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Richard Chiſwell,</hi> at the <hi>Roſe and Crown</hi> in St. <hi>Pauls</hi> Church-Yard.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Samuel Heyrick,</hi> at <hi>Grays-Inn-Gate</hi> in <hi>Holborn.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Robert Boulter,</hi> at the <hi>Turks-Head</hi> in <hi>Cornbill.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Thomas Paſſenger,</hi> at the <hi>Three Bibles</hi> on <hi>London-Bridge.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>William Battersby,</hi> at <hi>Thavies-Inn-Gate</hi> in <hi>Holborn.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Will. Leake</hi> and <hi>Jo. Leake,</hi> at the <hi>Crown</hi> in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Thomas Archer,</hi> under St. <hi>Dunſtan</hi>'s Church, <hi>Fleet-ſtreet.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Thomas Burrell,</hi> under St. <hi>Dunſtan</hi>'s Church, <hi>Fleet-ſtreet.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Edward Berry,</hi> in <hi>Grays-Inn.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Joſ. Robinſon,</hi> at <hi>Lincolns-Inn-Gate.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>John Leet,</hi> at <hi>Chancery-Lane</hi> end next <hi>Fleet-ſtreet.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Nich. Cox,</hi> over againſt <hi>Furnivals-Inne</hi> in <hi>Holborn</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
